<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Vaults]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/</link><image><url>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Vaults</title><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:24:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:24:15 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Cottage Industry]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This way something the came after the Enclosure Movement.<br>Where workers were working at a cottage to make money such as the large number of once famers.]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/cottage-industry.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Link it up/Cottage Industry.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 19:15:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crop Rotation]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Crop Rotation is like the name implies the rotation of crops to allow for the fields to be replenished, this would lead to the end of the one thirds field system as crop rotation would allow for crops to be replenished ]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/crop-rotation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Link it up/Crop Rotation.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:17:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ENCLOSURE MOVEMENT]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The enclouse movemnt was a movemnet in which large land owners would buy out or take the land of the peaseants and enclose it with something like fences, <br>Nobles also would take thier land share and enclose it off,<br>this would kick out peasants farmers with led to the decline of population in rural community's and this would lead to ppl needing work so they could survive. And this would also lead to the <a data-href="Cottage Industry" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/cottage-industry.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cottage Industry</a>.]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/enclosure-movement.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Link it up/ENCLOSURE MOVEMENT.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 19:14:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Open field system]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The open field system was a system in which a community of a village would have a shared land, which they would harvest and decide on the crops.<br>Divided in several large fields, which were in turn cut up into long, narrow strips.<br>The strips were had not been enclosed into small plots, still being open to anyone or thing.<br>The whole village followed a pattern of plowing, sowing, and harvesting in accordance with the traditions that have been around for a long time.<br>What was the reason behind using this system?
The reason behind this system was to give a full community effort. Where in this case everyone would work to gather as a sorta hive mind.
<br>What was a major deficiency of this system?
This system was deficient when it came to innovation because if someone wanted to try crop rotation for the first time everyone would have to come to a consensus and that made it really difficult because not everyone would be willing to do that because it wasn't a long standing tradition.
]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/open-field-system.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Link it up/Open field system.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 16:24:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[day 12 9]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>expansion is like ag, ppl count, modern stuff,<br>know scitists and vocab,<br>
common sense, <br>3 wyas europe expanded,<br>
ag revolition more food, more health ppl pop grows, ppl dont die as much,<br>
pop expansion more stuff,<br>
and econmic expansion, <br><br>gleaning: picking up the leftover stalks of grain after a field has been harvested<br>scatter the seeds on the top of the soil,<br>
leave half the land fallow,<br>
worked communally<br>
a shared common<br>production is very low<br>
1 bushel sown == 5-6 yield<br>
today 1=40 <br>a crop failure every 8-9 years,<br>crop failure was common<br>
famine foods - waht to eat when you can find nothingelse,<br>
chestnusts<br>
bark<br>
dandelions and grass<br>
straw<br>
resultls in massice pop loss,<br><br>1/3 of the land was left fallow each year.<br>land in rows - numerous farmers owned a strip of each field. <br>marginal land was held in common and all had access to it.<br>the mill, forest any extra pasturage was owned by the nobles. <br><br>da common pasturage avaable to all,<br><br>crop rotation the process of growing a series of diffrent plants on a specific field over consecutive seasons to change the nutriends demands on the soil. <br>significance crop rotations allows the elimination of the fallow no longer do lands need to be left unplanted so that they can renew their nutrient base. <br>if crop rotation is such a crop ration is a good idea they why would they resistet the change,<br>remember the price of failure: famine<br>
becuase lands were fairmed communally everyone in the village had to agree to try a new change -- a difficult task.<br>thus crop rotation didn't take off untill wealthy farmers claimed much of the land. <br>]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-9.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/day 12 9.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:15:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[day 12 10]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Encloser: when wealthy farmers bought out small farmers and enclosed the commons.<br>results small farmers could not survives without the commons and offten had to sell off thier lands.<br>if you dont mkae ends meat you have to sell the land,<br>cows and pigs on the commons and then you dont have to sell, and then when it gets closed off they have to sell their land, Midwest morgages,<br>
weaalhty farmers gained more and more land they were able experiment with new crops rotationn and selective breeding.<br>
doing a science experiment cant do that wiht the commons, <br>KNOW THE <a data-href="ENCLOSURE MOVEMENT" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/enclosure-movement.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">ENCLOSURE MOVEMENT</a><br><br>Carefully select which animals breed to try and select for certain desirable traits..<br>
results in bigger cattle, wooliter sheeps and pigs with more bacon.<br>
look at dog breeds, <br>Cannot be done if everyone just lets their animals wanders on the common. <br><br>English is the main starter,<br>
dutch golden age,<br>
dutch have to make an effort to improve their ag<br>
conditions in the netherlands (1650)<br>
Duthc pop was inc too rapidy for food supply to eep up<br>
needed to drasicty inc crop yield,<br>Hydrology -- the effective use of water tech to drain new crop land was importatn,<br>
they have to drain a lot fo their land, sea walls, dikes, experts, leaders in flood mitagation, how to controll the water, other contries notice and get dutch help, <br><br>
<br>Cornelius Vermuyden -- draining of swamp lands inc the amt of farmable acre.
<br>vicount charlse townshend -- turnips and other new crops, 
<br>Jethro Tull -- seed drill, hourse collar and selective  breeding, 
<br><br>The good<br>
rich got richer, good for nobles,<br>
ag production goes up<br>THE bad<br>
peasants could no longer make it when they lost access to the common and were forces to sell out<br>
Creation of large, rural, land-less working class,<br>
thsi will provide avablity workers for cottage inductry and eventually britains first factories that sounds good but if it was you would you consider it to be positive?<br>medievla pop fluctuated cus of freqtent crashes due to famines and other disasters this plague amd crop faileres this prevented pop from ever getting too high even thorught it rose during good times. <br><br>relativlely stable piop during earliers eras give way to massice inc,<br>
elimination of dramatic poplution chrashes the prvoius cycles led to the growth<br>fewer deaths not births, <br>Higher NIR because fewer people die for food surciety, <br><br>
<br>plague disappeared

<br>plauge was spread by flease that picked up plagues from europes black rats. after the black rats dieds of plague, they then bit humans -- not their preferred food
<br>in the age of exploration, asiaan brown rats rode ships to europes. they then compreted with ruope old rat species -- the black rat the great rat war was on! 
<br>the brown rats won the war. but the flies dont like the taste of brown rats. since the flease didn't bite the brown rat  the could no longer transfer plague from rats to people
<br>1720 in marseille: france experienced the last major ourbreak of plague in europe,


]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-10.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/day 12 10.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:16:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[day 12 11]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>improved water supplies new water supply systems brought clean water to cities so that they didn't have to draw from filthy rivers<br>sewers systme -- pppl prevoiuselt just dumpbed their fiths on the sterees a small imporvemtn goesa logn way<br>drain swampland doen to increase available farmland but reduced the mosquito population<br><br>Improved transportation -- better roasds and canals prevented localized famines in the past a town could starve even if another town 20 miles away had extra food<br>new crops potatoes turnnips and others new crops provided better nutition and more calories per acre<br>improved medicine WAS NOOOOOTTT the answer!!!<br>this is the answer modern americans would exprect but it did not impact death totals yet<br>
european medical techniques were limited in what they could accomplish. <br>blood lettiing was their "best" tecnicq<br><br>europe didn't try to reuce the death rate<br>
didn't know the brown rat was new.<br>
clean water made more pleasant drinking<br>
link to health wasn't known.<br>sewers were to reduce the smell<br>swamps drained for farmland. not becuase of the misquetoes<br>
roads built to make money on trade, not for peoples communitcation<br>nwe crops more calorides<br>
nobody knew they were more nutitious.<br>better food nutiontsn you are then stronger water is better sewer is better plauge is mostly gone.<br><br>Rural Villages<br>
the vast majority of people lived in small self sufficient villages.<br>
almost every thing you used was made by either your faily or someone in the same town<br>
the concept of going to work<br>
didn't exipse as they didn't leave home and din't earn money, you are at work all the time, work is with you.<br>
the combination of enclosure and population pressure puts presuse on the system<br>town life<br>
guilds control most of the ecoonomic life of a town.<br>
guilds an association of artiasans merchants who oversee their particular craft/trade in a ceertain area. aprrechtist, the juny man, and then a master were you need to prosent a master peice, then you can make your own shop<br>
it was illega to operate within a town if you were not a member of the appropriate guild<br>
guilds were restrictive (monopolistic) but also protected workers and consumers<br>all this gets meessed up cus farmers got kicked out,]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-11.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/day 12 11.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:15:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[day 12 12]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>cleaner water wanted it to taste better, <br>not a lot of ppl will have coin in a rural village, sabeth is the only 'break' and then some hollidays,<br>
guilds are the domant oganization in the towns, they are the monopolists, they controll every thing you cant just start making bricks they stifle production, but there are standards and no change or inavation it threatens<br><br>a system fo mass production that took place ein the dcottage.<br>
made use of skills people already had.<br>
employed man famrers who were landless aferer enclousre.<br>there was a mass of farmers that could be workers and they are looking for work, <br>domestis sys<br>
1600s early 1700s cloth was made by the domestuc system. most of the wordk was doen in the cottages of the workers whole families workerd togehter.<br>sottage was done in your house, the builnesi owner would provide mitereals and then its your job to put it together for the owner,<br>
it was orginlay the raw mitrails then it goes to specillized to the houses, and the owner sells the finshied product, and they dont need to be payed as much, they guilds only really have the power in the town, if there is a michenine that put people out of work and made things faster they guilds hate it but the builness owner love it, and industy skipp the guilds and they go to the country side and are nto payed to much, payed by the piece piece work.<br>
and they need the money they have nothing else to do,<br>
alot of it is family run, aslong as you can do it you work, <br>and if you keep scraps the owners would get really mad,<br><br>skill peasants already possessed<br>
not for them selfs but for an owner,<br>the loom is much more complex micheine, it was uselly run by a man,<br>
there was and anverg peaceie per day, and they were "payed"!<br><br>The change from a system vbased on producution for personal use to a markcert based ecnonomy -- production goods for sale to other,<br>
why am i making something, the personal element goes away, and they are getting payed in cash, you get money, and that changed the econmay and you get payed in money and the baker has to take the money, and the owner doesn't want the shirts to be barted cus they are his, and this allowed people to marry younger, and there are kids that could help, finances situation , you have to have your own stuff, and farming comuntiys would wait to build up a base, and people that get marryed young would struggle and they have yet to max out their earning poental, and you wouldn't have to wait for the death of a family member for the land,<br>Atlantic Econmy, there are cononlitys out were there, for trade spieces raw matireals, and they cant go takeover a pplace that has a stonger goverment and the coniles were weak, and if your a conlinist are not happy, the french or dutch goods are better for america and england lose your natrual reasrouse and buy it back,<br>how does it impact the economy,<br><br>traditional mercantilitsm an economy run by and fof the state. It increased exports and decreased imports to benefit the goverment. be selling more stuff then you are buying, make more money then you spend<br>britichs mercantilsim -- mercantilist style policies but with the belief that goverment poliices should serve private as well as state intrests the belief was that wealthy citizends were good fro the country, why set up a buinnise ecept to make money, if it only goes to the goverment it is not great but britsish govement is not as helavy taxed, and so britan is a dominatin foreigne invester,<br><br>all goods entering the british empire must be carrieed on a britsih ship manned by british crew.<br>
consolidating the money<br>colonies muyst buty goods from britain if it was possible, which could be a big deal becaause french goods could be cheaper or better, so all the money goes back into britain,<br>if goods were purchased from outside of the empire, those goods must go throught london before moving on to some other part of the empire. people would lie about wieght and cargo, controlling the money and the flow, <br>purpose of the navigaion acts 
<br>colonies exist to serve the home countirs provide jobs in britain. the colonies provided a guaranetedd markcer for bristais makufacting a squiteel could go from there to here far with out touching the gorund,<br>
developmnet of skilled merchants marine ships sailors<br>
hurt the Dutch! the biggest rival for over seas trade, the dutch control stuff like wall street wall there, 2 or 3 wars with the dutch then british and french fight several times, <br>]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-12.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/day 12 12.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:21:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[day 12 12 Ap euro bit by bit number 23]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>a half to a thrid of the land was not used<br>england and the netherlands were the main, and they used the scifticf revoluitons <br>use of new technocy for ag protechs<br>
charles townsmen used crops to replesnish the soil,<br>
newterns on the soil then it would replenish the soil,<br>
and menoure for fertalizer, <br>more food for livestock and fresh meat, not rotten,<br>jethor toll, for the seeed drill, mechinized mechine that would allow a farmer to plant a row of crops at a length and depts for better yeilds,<br>new crops from the new world,<br>
potatos corn, tomatoes,<br>
ireland was the potatoes, eaten all the time sustain a population,<br>
but then the potation famine happend becuase they were standing on one leg,<br>changed the face of ag diffrent foods supports lot more people,<br>enclousre movement starts in england, large land owners wants sheep for fabrics and which will be the begins of the industial revolutions, and it was the farms that were communal,<br>to bolster the price of crops in england, they put terifs on grains and that drives up prices for food in england, and it help the large land owners, and country side people forced of their land and they had to move to town and citys and they need work, and whould help the instrial revoelion and the agricualt revolition had impacts of populaiton of explorions more poepl are born because of food and changed the life style of the country side, and the scientifc method, basis of comuunaly, a depopulation of pppl in the coutry side, sewage probelems and houseing,<br>
change in the staus of women, they were equal in the farming, now in the scientif aproch they devoled to a domestic role and they become more demestisized take care of children working in mills,<br>creationg of consumerism, less spent on food so they want more products,<br><a data-href="day 12 12" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-12.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">day 12 12</a>]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-12-ap-euro-bit-by-bit-number-23.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/day 12 12 Ap euro bit by bit number 23.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 19:10:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[day 12 12 crash course number 8]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>changes in the lives that poeple would live,<br>game of thoreons, not game of sliglthy improved seed quilitys,<br>politic touches everythign but politices isn't everything,<br>goign to shcool and what you get to eat,<br>citizents of today has great HDI<br>in 15 hougnread in the 14 centry a famine, trae was local and regulated by guilds in the late middle ages subsistance ag,<br>princes were allone in geting a full stomach<br>in 1500-1750<br>
situslaw graduily improved, population rosse in britsain population doubles in 1700-1800<br>
an agricaluear revoluion and a comicerial revoluion and columbion extraions,<br>and there was inavation, and plant chertan criops would replenish the osil and this would become crop rotation and this decrease the farm land that would need to be fallow, and dutch would alllow for land reclammationa and farm land were enclosuaes, private farms could inavate faster, seed drill, and plow, coppyed chinese inventains, more food and wealhty, not every one enifts and fewer people had direct acess to tier stuff,<br>in scotaland, elizbeth removed tentands and then had sheep,<br>
and day workers didn't have claims, and she chased away with her own hands, and mroe food but control by fewer people, migraiont of disenfrancised,<br>ideas of property private is common day, <br>to some it was fatal but it allowed for food for people and shakesearer were writing because the food, and<br>
potato wsa very important,<br>
you dont need great soil for the potato,<br>
americas and africas gave better inavations?<br>enslaved women agricalutists aor learnsing?<br>stoping at 8:03 for video in charcourse<br><a data-href="day 12 12" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-12.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">day 12 12</a>]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-12-crash-course-number-8.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/day 12 12 crash course number 8.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 19:10:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[day 12 13]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>his book an inquiry into the nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations (1776)<br>
is basically defining book on capitalism.<br>make as much money as you can, <br>private choices of the consumer and producer lead to the strongest economy.<br>goverment shouldn't get in the way to much,<br>
private choiece leads to the best economy, we have private company that want you to buy stuff, <br>if everyone acts iin their own self intresst thee economy overall is best served. "Greed is Good!"<br>govermeent intervent in the ecnoom should be kept to a minimum<br>what about your food, <br>some do well some dont.]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-13.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/day 12 13.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 15:51:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Day 12 16]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The avger people (women, poor) instead of a focus on monarchs, wars, etc.<br>Major trends in chapert 18<br>appearances matter many of the divisions betweene esocial classes coem down to appearances. the upper lower class wants everyone to know that they aren't at the bottom. the middle class wants people to know they arnets manual laboreres. the wealthy middle class attempts to copy the nobility<br>moving to cities matters many o fthe cjanges in daily life stem from many poeple no longer living in small self sufficeint villages. consider the lack of familial supervision on the young.<br>
class differences matter life is not the same for the rich and the poor. this impacts everything<br>class diffrense matter life is not he same for the rich and the poor this impacts everything.<br>conspicuqas consumsion.<br>
nice house strugling to pay bills<br>
]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-16.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Textnotes/Day 12 16.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:52:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Page 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>Watch AP Euro Bit-by-Bit #23 (and the first 7:30 of Crash Course #8) and answer the following questions (Ch 17 pages 494-503)<br>
NOTE: Up to this moment, we have really been focusing on many of the major political, religious, and economic developments that were occurring in Europe beginning with the rise of the Renaissance in the early 1400s, the development of multiple Christian denominations during the 1500s, and all culminating in the development of absolutism throughout much of Europe by the early 1700s. However, while these events and movements did significantly impact the over-all course of Europe’s development on a continental scale, for the vast number of Europeans living during this time period, the day-to-day life experiences from generation to generation did not change all that drastically. Remember, although influential, the middle class by no means was a true representation of Europe’s population as a whole. By the late 1600s, at least 80% of the Western European population still relied on agriculture as their primary livelihood and this number was certainly higher in the kingdoms of Eastern Europe.<br>
<br>1.Describe the purpose of the Open-field system of agriculture. GoTo <a data-href="Open field system" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/open-field-system.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Open field system</a>
Open field system<br><br>The open field system was a system in which a community of a village would have a shared land, which they would harvest and decide on the crops.<br>Divided in several large fields, which were in turn cut up into long, narrow strips.<br>The strips were had not been enclosed into small plots, still being open to anyone or thing.<br>The whole village followed a pattern of plowing, sowing, and harvesting in accordance with the traditions that have been around for a long time.<br>What was the reason behind using this system?
The reason behind this system was to give a full community effort. Where in this case everyone would work to gather as a sorta hive mind.
<br>What was a major deficiency of this system?
This system was deficient when it came to innovation because if someone wanted to try crop rotation for the first time everyone would have to come to a consensus and that made it really difficult because not everyone would be willing to do that because it wasn't a long standing tradition.

<br>NOTE: During the 1700s, England and the Netherlands led, what historians now refer to as, an Agricultural Revolution. Drawing upon the ideas of the Scientific Revolution, these countries worked towards improving agricultural output, making use of a variety of new technology, methods, and access to new foods.<br>2. One of the major innovations during the Agricultural Revolution was the use of crop rotation. What is Crop Rotation and why was it an improvement over the open field system?
<a data-href="Crop Rotation" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/crop-rotation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Crop Rotation</a> Crop Rotation<br><br>Crop Rotation is like the name implies the rotation of crops to allow for the fields to be replenished, this would lead to the end of the one thirds field system as crop rotation would allow for crops to be replenished <br>
It is an improvement over the open field system as the open field system would be a consensus with the community so change would be hard so it would still be the continuation of the one thirds field system so it would also then give nuitreinst to the soil and crops.
<br>2a. How did it also impact livestock (and thus ultimately people’s diets)?
This would give more food for the live stock as there would be more food for the people. So it would impact their diet by giving more protein / nutrients into their diet. 
<br>3. How did the Columbian Exchange ultimately impact the Agricultural Revolution in Europe?
The Columbian Exchange impacted the Agricultural Revolution in Europe by giving rise to crop rotation which came about due to the enclosure movement and that collimated to give a better diet. And crop rotation could come about due to the New Crops coming from the Columbain Exchange.
<br>3a. According to John Greene (Crash Course), why is the potato the world’s most important plant of the last 500 years?
<a data-href="day 12 12 crash course number 8" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/textnotes/day-12-12-crash-course-number-8.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">day 12 12 crash course number 8</a> &lt;&lt; notes on video<br>
John Greene stated that the potato didn't need great soil. So with that they could be planted pretty much anywhere and they would grow.
<br>4. In what sense did Jethro Tull’s seed drill represent not only a mechanical but also a scientific agricultural improvement?
Jethro Tull's seed drill represent a mechanical improvement because it was the yield improvement in the field for the seed were planted into the soil which then would allow them to germinate better which is the scientific advanment.
<br><br><br>5. What was the enclosure movement and how did it represent a more scientific approach to agriculture?
The enclosure movement was<br>
<a data-href="ENCLOSURE MOVEMENT" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/enclosure-movement.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">ENCLOSURE MOVEMENT</a>  ENCLOSURE MOVEMENT<br><br>The enclouse movemnt was a movemnet in which large land owners would buy out or take the land of the peaseants and enclose it with something like fences, <br>Nobles also would take thier land share and enclose it off,<br>this would kick out peasants farmers with led to the decline of population in rural community's and this would lead to ppl needing work so they could survive. And this would also lead to the <a data-href="Cottage Industry" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/cottage-industry.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cottage Industry</a>.<br>
it represented the ability for more land to be used for experiments like the new idea of <a data-href="crop rotation" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/crop-rotation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">crop rotation</a>. 
<br>5a. How did it impact the land owners?
First the peasant farmers were forced to sell their land because they could not longer use the commons. So they would have to die, more to town to find work or start work in the <a data-href="cottage industry" href="https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/link-it-up/cottage-industry.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">cottage industry</a><br>
Second would be the gentlemen farmer which they would buy the land that the peasant farmers left and would begin to stuff to make money.
<br>5b. How did it impact the peasant farmers?

<br>Forced to sell their land 
<br>Find new work or starve.

<br>Brain Challenge #1: Who benefits?<br>
The agricultural revolution had a significantly different impact on the rich and the poor. How a<br>
person felt about the developments might well depend on their social status/<br>
A. How did the agricultural revolution impact wealthy landowners?<br>
B. How did the agricultural revolution impact poor farmers?<br>
C. Given both its short and long-term impacts, was the agricultural revolution a good thing?<br>6. In a nutshell, what were the major impacts of the agricultural revolution on European society (especially the British and the Dutch)? Be sure to give a brief description of each impact.

<br>Healthier life more nutrients in food,
<br>More land for the Dutch becasue they got rid of the low land waters
<br>More food from the use of crop rotation
<br>Encolusre movement which drove peasant farmers to work in a town or in the cttage industy 

<br><br><br>NOTE: As shown by the previous section, the agricultural revolution during the late 17 th and early 18 th centuries had a dramatic impact on society. That said, it must be noted that these impacts varied from region to region depending on things such as how aggressive countries were in implementing these new techniques and ideas as well as what political system was in use at the time (think Eastern vs Western absolutism as well as absolutism vs constitutional systems). With that in mind, these movements eventually led to what is now referred to as the industrious revolution (not to be confused with the industrial revolution). Watch AP Euro Bit-by-Bit #24 and answer the following questions (Ch 17 pages 503-508)<br>7. Since the Middle Ages, many businesses had operated under the Guild system. In general, what was a Guild?
A guild was like a govermental deparment but it had nothing to due with the goverment,
<br>7a. What were the benefits of the guild system?
They would train workers, they had fixed prices for what was sold, they gave fair wages, and regulated waht was sold
<br>7b. What were some disadvantages of the guild system?
The guild system would curb inovation into new tech that wouldn't be work done by man. And they would run you out of town if you were not affiliated with the guild.
<br>8. Describe the putting-out system. How did it work?
The beginning of the putting out system was were a wealthy business owner would give raw products to a worker and they would make a quota and they would get a wage, then later in the putting out system workers would become speiclized, they also didn't own the object that were made. that being uselly textiles.
<br>Brain Challenge #2: Urban vs. Rural<br>
In modern America we usually associated the manufacturing of goods with large urban factories,<br>
yet the first significant production of for-market production took place in rural areas. (Cottage<br>
industry and the putting out system.) In the early modern era what were the advantages or<br>
disadvantages offered by each of the following locations:<br>
A. Urban Areas:<br>
B. Rural Areas:<br>9. What was the reason for the development of what became known as the putting-out system (or Cottage industry)?
The formation of colonies that did not have the mean to produce the textiles
<br>9a. Why was this advantageous for entrepreneurs?
Because they could make a lot of money 
<br>9b. Why was this advantageous for farm laborers?
They may make more money 
<br><br><br>10. When compared with cottage industries, list and give a description of 2 advantages of the guild system.

<br>Standerided wages
<br>Better work safety/ workers comp.

<br>NOTE: As you have hopefully realized, both the agricultural revolution and the industrious revolution (including the putting out system) resulted, not only from the implementation of ideas stemming from the Scientific Revolution, but also from the age of exploration (including the colonization of the New World along and expanded trade with Africa and Asia). Pages 634-647in the textbook serve as a good review of this material. Watch the Enlightenment Thinkers video (4:25-10:30) AND read the textbook pages 508--514, then answer the following questions<br>11. What were the main ideas behind the economic theory of mercantilism?
Gain more gold from exports and don't lose gold due to imports
<br>11a. In this system (mercantilism), what was the role of the government?
The role of the government would be the main regulator and controler it wasn't as laissez-faire
<br>NOTE: Whereas many Enlightenment ideas such as freedom of speech and religious belief conflicted with restrictions resulting from stringent political systems such as absolutism, the ideas of Adam Smith focused more on problems stemming from the absolutist economic theory of the time: Mercantilism. His book, Inquiry into the Nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations (1776) established the basis for modern economics.<br>12. How did the Enlightenment idea of selfishness and the individual play a role in Adam Smith’s economic theory?
It would tie into a laissez-faire system where individuals of a society would control the market a free market, as they would have control they could decided what they do as they see fit.
<br>12a. According to Smith, what is the Invisible Hand? (why is it invisible?)
Basicly the forces that control the market, no one can really predict what the market will do. 
<br>12b. How is this theory a reaction to Mercantilism?
Because Mercantilism was administered by the government a gave little choice to private individuals, thus people should control the market not the government. 
<br>12c. Given your answers to the above questions, why would the notion of competition (free market) be so vital to Smith’s ideas?
Because it would make companies have to innovate and have the best prices and best quality for them to stay in business, thus it being a moving force and being vital. 
<br>13. According to Adam Smith, what were the 3 duties a government should limit itself to?

<br>natinal defense
<br>administration of justice 
<br>public goods.

<br><br><br>Brain Challenge #3: Would the creation of public schools fit under Smith’s umbrella of governmental<br>
responsibilities? Why or why not?<br>The Changing Life of the People<br>Chapter 18<br>There will not be a typical reading guide for chapter 18. Instead you will need to use the basic information in creating your character sketch. There are, however, some vocabulary terms for the chapter. Define the following terms/phrases being sure to be thorough enough that your definitions are meaningful.<br>
<br>
Community Controls

<br>the soical level of the individual their power


<br>
Illegitimacy Explosion

<br>s


<br>
Infanticide

<br>how many child have died


<br>
“Spare the rod and spoil the child”

<br>
Just Price

<br>
Consumer Society

<br>consumerism, people spending time buying products


<br>
Edward Jenner. What did he do?

<br>
Methodists

<br>
Blood Sports

]]></description><link>https://pythongithcode.github.io/AP-EURO/10th-graade/ap-euro/ap-eupo/chapter-17/main-text-notes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">10th graade/AP EURO/AP eupo/Chapter 17/Main text notes.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:58:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>